瞬！ どうして…？
Shun!
Why?
瞬…
Shun…
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
あ…
合流できて よかったです
It is good that we have reunited.
乾さんはどうされました？
Where is Inui-san?
I…
私… 瞬に… 覚はどうしたの？
Shun…
Where is Satoru?
近くの洞窟におられます
He is in a cave nearby.
ケガをされているので
He was injured, so I left alone to find you and Inui-san.
私が お二人を
捜しに行くところだったのですが
ケガ？
大したことはありません
Injured?
It is nothing grave.
どうして ケガをしたの？
How did he get injured?
悪鬼に追われた時に
When the Fiend was pursuing us,
a piece of rock hit him from above.
砕け散った岩の破片が
当たったのです
だいぶ まばらになってきました
急ぎましょう
There are far fewer bats now.
Let us hurry.
Episode Twenty-Four
Torchlight in the Darkness
Saki!
早季！ 無事で良かった！
心配してたんだ！
I’m so glad you’re okay.
I was worried.
乾さんは？
Where’s Inui-san?
亡くなったわ
あ…
He died.
ゴカイの化け物に襲われたの
A giant ragworm attacked him.
乾さん 一人だったら
身を守ることはできた
He would have survived on his own.
でも 私を守ろうとして…
But he tried to protect me…
早季 乾さんの犠牲は
無駄にはしないよ
We won’t let his sacrifice be in vain, Saki.
うん… 見つけたの
これも 乾さんのおかげだわ
I found it.
It wouldn’t have been possible without Inui-san.
見つけたって まさか…
You found it? Do you mean…
Here, look.
これよ
気をつけてね うっかり割ったら
一巻の終わりだから
Careful.
We’re doomed if it breaks.
使うときは相手の足元に
たたきつければいいみたい
I think it’s enough if we smash it open in his path when the time comes.
分かった
Okay.
No. You’re injured.
だめよ ケガしているのに…
私が持ってるわ
I’ll carry it.
俺だって こいつをたたきつける
くらいのことならできるよ
I’m not injured so badly that I can’t smash this open.
それなら私だって
But I can do the job too.
Let’s take turns, then.
じゃあ 交替で持つことにしよう
まず 最初は俺だ
I’ll go first.
Lingering too long is dangerous.
同じ場所へ
とどまっているのは危険です
Let us move out.
そろそろ移動しましょう
What do we do now?
これからどうするの？
当初の目的である
With the retrieval of the Psychobuster, we have fulfilled our main objective.
サイコバスターの入手は
果たせました
いったん 引き揚げるのも
一案だとは思います
Withdrawing for the time being seems sound to me.
しかし 逆に 今は
千載一遇の好機かもしれません
On the other hand, this might be an incredibly rare opportunity.
我々の戦略目標である悪鬼が
The focal point of our strategies, the Fiend, has only a weak escort and is close to our position.
少々の護衛しかつけずに
すぐ そばにいるのです
有利な点は まだあります
There is another advantage to this.
敵は あくまで
我々を狩るつもりでしょうが
The enemy believes they are hunting us,
狩りに夢中になっている者ほど
but in their dazed pursuit they will not realize
until the end that they have become the hunted.
自分が獲物になることに
寸前まで気付かないものです
しかも やつらは
Additionally, they do not know that
we have obtained the Psychobuster.
我々がサイコバスターを
入手したことを知りません
この機を逃す手は ないでしょう
Should we really pass up this chance?
すごく嫌な臭い
The stink is terrible.
コウモリのふんです
It is bat guano.
やつらは お二方の臭跡には
They pursue your scent like madmen, but for some reason I do not seem to evoke much fascination.
目の色を変えて
追って来るんですが
私の方は なぜか全く
食指が動かないようなのです
どうして？
Why?
I guess they are not very interested in me to begin with.
ま もともと
あまり興味がないんでしょうな
私など放っておいても
大した脅威にならないと
Perhaps they believe that I would not be much of a threat, even if left to my own devices.
高をくくっているのかも
しれませんね
Kiroumaru dealt them a serious blow.
奇狼丸は
敵に大打撃を与えたからね
Maybe they want to keep their distance.
むしろ 敬遠したいかも
敵を７匹は倒したしね
He took out seven of them.
そんなに？
That many?
これは まずい
雨が降り始めたようです
This is not good.
It has begun to rain.
急ぎましょう
短期決戦にするしかなさそうです
Let us make haste.
We can only wager it all on one push now.
この先 １ｋｍほど続いて
地上に出ますが
This tunnel goes on for a kilometer before reaching the surface.
都合のいいことに途中 ほとんど
分岐点のない 一本道なんです
It helps greatly that there are hardly any junctions for the length of the tunnel.
Why does that help?
どうして都合がいいんだ？
It means we can only escape in one direction.
逃げ道が
一方向しかないってことだろう？
The enemy can only come from one direction as well.
追手は背後の
一方向から来るだけですから
距離をとりやすいでしょう
We can easily keep them at a distance.
穴は途中で複雑に
左右に曲がっていますから
There are many curves and bends along the tunnel,
完全に追いつかれない限り
so you will not be in view of the Fiend until he has caught up with you.
悪鬼の視界に入ることも
ありません
途中 数本の脇道がありますが
The tunnel branches numerous times, but if we follow the main path, we should not get lost.
道なりに進めば
迷うことはありません
本当に ここが最適なのかな？
Is this really such a smart idea?
我々の目的において
これ以上の場所はありません
There is no better place for our purposes.
最大の利点は この風です
The main advantage is the breeze here.
背後の悪鬼は風下ってわけか…
そうだな
The Fiend is downwind if he comes after us, huh?
You’re right.
悪い兆候ですな
予想以上の豪雨になりそうです
This is a bad omen.
The rain is heavier than I had expected.
My original plan was sound, but it has become quite unreliable.
当初の計画では 十分に機能するか
心もとなくなってきました
では 誘導に行ってまいります
Well then. I shall lead them in.
どうぞ ご無事で
I pray for your safety.
足元は思ったより良かったな
大丈夫？ 覚えた？
The footing here is better than expected.
You okay? Remember the way back?
私が迷うのは
分かれ道があるときだけ
I only get lost when there are junctions.
ここは 一本道だもん
There’s only one way to go here.
それ… 私が持ってた方が
いいんじゃない？
Shouldn’t I carry that?
覚は両手をケガしてるし…
Your arms are injured.
このくらい どうってことないよ
This is no big deal.
Besides, I’m good at throwing things.
それに投てきは
俺の方が得意だったじゃないか
でも…
早季が転んで
But…
We’d be in big trouble if you stumbled and crushed this.
これを割っちゃったら
最悪だからな
本当に できるのかしら？
Will it all work out?
私たち １人の人間を
殺そうとしてるのよ
We’re trying to kill a human being.
Stop it.
よせって… そんなこと考えるな
Don’t think about it.
We’re only going to smash this open in his path.
俺らはただ 悪鬼の前に
これをたたきつけるだけなんだ
それで悪鬼が
すぐに死ぬわけじゃないし
The Fiend won’t die immediately either.
ごめん 変なこと言って…
Sorry.
I shouldn’t have said that.
Don’t worry.
いいよ
ただ使命を果たすだけなんだ
We just have to fulfill our mission.
今は それ以外のことは
頭から締め出そう
Let’s ignore everything else.
うん でもね
真理亜と守の子どもは
Okay.
But is Maria’s and Mamoru’s child really a Fiend?
本当に悪鬼なのかな？
That again?
また その話か？
You know how many villagers he’s slaughtered!
町の人たちを虐殺したんだぞ
悪鬼以外になんだっていうんだよ
How can he not be a Fiend?
分かってる 私も見たよ
I know, I saw it too.
We can think about it all once we’ve stopped him.
悪鬼を止めてから
ゆっくり考えればいいよ
私は どうしても…
I just can’t shake off the feeling…
Cut it out!
いいかげんにしてくれ！
Why do you keep saying things that make it so complicated?!
今さら どうして俺を
惑わせるようなことを言うんだ
ごめん！ でも聞いて！
Sorry! But listen!
もしかしたら あのコは
自分が何者だか
I can’t help but feel that maybe he
just doesn’t know that he’s human!
分かってないだけじゃないかって
気がしてしょうがないのよ
So?
だから？ どっちにしても
止めるしかないだろ？
We have to stop him anyway!
そうしなきゃ 町は全滅だ
Everyone in the villages is going to die if we don’t!
I know that! I know!
分かってるわよ！ 分かってる
でも 真理亜の子どもなのよ
But it’s Maria’s child!
一度でいいからチャンスを…
Shouldn’t we at least give him a chance?
チャンス？ 何を言ってるのか
分かってんのか？
A chance? Are you out of your mind?
もし あのコに
気付かせることさえできたら！
What if there’s a way to let him know he’s human?
This—
あ これ…
しっ！
狩りが
始まった
The hunt…
It has begun.
That’s Kiroumaru!
奇狼丸だ！
どういうことなの？
What do you mean?
The rain will wash away our scent trail.
臭跡は水に流れてしまいます
敵には今がチャンスと思わせ
We need to goad them into attacking us before they can consider the situation.
考える間もなく
跡を追わせなくてはいけません
そのためには
もっと強力な まき餌…
We need a better bait…
いや はっきりとした おとりが
必要になります
No, a more obvious bait for that.
ちょっと待って
おとりっていうのは…
Hold on.
What do you mean?
You two will have to show yourselves to the enemy, even if it is only for a moment.
お二人には少なくとも 一瞬は
敵に姿を見せていただかなくては
いけません
すぐさま 穴の中に逃げ込めば
If you promptly escape into a tunnel, the Fiend should lose his composure and pursue you.
悪鬼は
我を忘れて追ってくるでしょう
何 言ってるんだよ
Are you crazy?
You’re telling us to play Tag with the Fiend?
悪鬼と
鬼ごっこしろっていうのか？
向こうの視界に捉えられたら
それで終わりなんだぞ
We’re done for if we get in his line of sight.
無理よ とてもできない
Impossible. We can’t possibly do that.
Impossible? What do you mean?
できない？ どういうことですか？
だって そんな…
But… We…
How many do you think have been sacrificed to get you this far?
ここに来るまでに
いったい どれほどの犠牲が
積み重ねられたと
思っているんですか？
They all died so you could have this one moment,
全ては悪鬼を倒すことができる
ただ 一瞬のためです
this one chance to defeat the Fiend.
全員 それを信じて
自らの命をなげうってまで
Did they not trust you enough that they were willing to pay the ultimate price?
お二人に希望を
託したのではないですか？
Yes, you’re right.
分かってる 君の言うとおりだ
たった 一つの目的のために
We came here, ready to lay down our lives, with one goal in mind.
命を捨てるつもりで
ここへ来たのに…
私には お二人に
強制することはできません
I cannot force you.
それどころか
あなた方の げきりんに触れた瞬間
On the contrary, I would be no more than a worm crushed by your wrath should I invoke your ire.
虫けらのように
ひねり潰されてしまう
存在でしかない
お決めになるのは
あくまでも あなた方ご自身です
The decision is yours to make.
来るぞ！
They’re coming!
早季 早季！ 大丈夫だ！
Saki. Saki!
It’s okay.
ゆっくり来ているみたいだ
They seem to be moving slowly.
おかしいぞ
瞬なの？
This is strange.
Shun?
This is strange. Don’t you agree?
おかしい 変だと思わないか？
変？ 変って何が？
Strange? What’s strange?
聞こえるだろう
Can’t you hear it?
危ない これは わなだ
Watch out! It’s a trap!
どうして？
Why?
気付かないのか？ さっきから
悪鬼は追ってきていない
Don’t you see?
You aren’t being chased by the Fiend.
早季？
Saki…
Satoru, this is a trap.
覚 これは わなよ
何 言ってるんだ
What are you talking about?
悪鬼は追いかけて来ないわ
どうしてだと思う？
The Fiend isn’t coming after us.
Any idea why?
知るか！ こんなことしてたら
すぐに追いつかれるぞ！
Hell if I know!
We need to get going or they’ll catch up!
このまま戻ろう
戻るって どっちに？
Let’s go back.
Go back where?
最初に走ってきた方
The direction we came from.
But the Fiend’s there!
悪鬼がいるんだぞ？
No, he isn’t.
いないじゃない
えっ…
Don’t you get it?
分からない？
今のは わなだったのよ
This was a trap.
Yakomaru predicted which way we’d run and made the tunnel collapse.
野狐丸は
私たちが逃げる方向を読んで
崩落をしかけたんだわ
奇狼丸もグルだったのかな？
Is Kiroumaru in on it too?
I don’t know.
それは分からないけど…
Either way, it’s suicide to keep on going.
とにかく
あっちに行くのは自殺行為よ
敵は私たちを
待ち伏せしてるんだから
The enemy’s lying in ambush.
最初から だまされていたんだ！
We’ve been played!
逃げよう
Let’s run.
どうしたの？
What’s wrong?
I’ll try what you suggested!
早季の提案 やってみる うん…
もし あのコに
気付かせることさえできたら…
If he realizes what he is…
あのコは
バケネズミに育てられたから
That boy was raised by the queerats,
自分をバケネズミだと思ってる
so he thinks he’s a queerat himself.
鏡を見たら どうなると思う？
鏡？
What do you think will happen when he looks into a mirror?
A mirror?
私 バケネズミのコロニーで
鏡を見たことないの
Queerats don’t have mirrors, from what I’ve seen.
自分がバケネズミだと
思っていたコが
He thinks he’s a queerat, but what if he
realizes he looks like his human enemies?
自らの姿が 敵である
人間そのものだと知ったら…
よく見て あなたは人間なの
Look closely.
You’re human.
真理亜と守の かけがえのない
You’re Maria and Mamoru’s child.
ギャ～！
危ない！ 逃げろ！
Watch out! Run!
覚！
Satoru!
早季 逃げろ
えっ？
Saki, run!
I’ll end it here.
これで終わりにする
No! Stop!
だめ… やめて！
Take this!
受け取れ！
これで全てが終わる
This would put an end to it all.
Our mission would finally be over.
私たちの使命は ようやく完了した
私たちが どうなるにせよ
No matter what became of us,
悪鬼は滅びるだろう
the Fiend would go down.
Kamisu’s 66th district would be saved,
and peace and order would be restored.
そして 神栖66町は救われ
再び 平和と秩序が訪れる
No.
違う この距離では悪鬼だけでなく
At this distance, the Psychobuster will infect both Satoru and the Fiend.
覚まで
サイコバスターに感染してしまう
One by one, I’ve lost my loved ones.
私は これまで
愛する人を次々と失ってきた
My sister. Shun.
姉 瞬 そして 真理亜と守まで…
Then Maria and Mamoru.
この上 覚まで失ったら
私は 独りぼっちになってしまう
If I lose Satoru as well, I’ll be all alone.
私たちの 一班は
私 一人しか残らないではないか
I’ll be the only one left from Group One.
そんなことが 本当に
神の望んだ結末だというのか？
Is this truly the will of the gods?
嫌だ！
No!
ウ ギャ～…
Run!
逃げよう！
早季
Saki…
いいから早く！
Just hurry up!
奇狼丸！
Kiroumaru?
That way!
あちらへ
まだ追ってこないようですな
He still has not come after us.
They might be treating his burns first.
先に手当てを
するのかもしれません
Where are we going now?
これから どこへ行くの？
I do not know.
分かりません とりあえず
悪鬼から隔たることが先決です
Let us put some distance between ourselves and the Fiend for now.
ごめんなさい
私のせいでサイコバスターは…
I’m sorry.
It’s my fault that the Psychobuster went to waste.
悠長に後悔している暇は
ありません
There is no time to lament that.
Concentrate on the path ahead.
前方にも注意してください
Yakomaru’s soldiers might be lying in ambush.
野狐丸が
伏兵を置いているかもしれません
悪鬼の臭いです
I smell the Fiend.
ようやく
追いついてきたようですな
They have finally caught up to us.
It seems they know that we are here.
どうやら 我々がここにいることは
分かっているようです
もう だめだ
We’re finished.
We’re pinned down and we’ve lost our trump card, the Psychobuster.
身動きもとれず 切り札だった
サイコバスターも失った
これまでだ…
This is the end.
そうと決めつけるのは
早いかもしれません
It might be too early to give up.
何か いい考えでもあるの？
You’ve got an idea?
いや ここに至っては
No. I do not believe there is a way out.
確かに手の打ちようがないように
見えます
しかし 野狐丸の方も
一気に決着をつけることは
However, Yakomaru appears to have no immediate solution for this either.
できずにいるようです
こちらには
まだ最後の手段があります
We still have our last resort.
敵と 一緒に
生き埋めになるのを覚悟して
If you can accept being buried alive along with the enemy,
呪力で洞窟を
破壊してしまうことです
you can collapse the cave using your Cantus.
Is that Yakomaru’s fear? Is that why he’s not attacking us?
野狐丸は それが怖くて
私たちを
追いつめられないでいるの？
He might be having trouble coming up with his final move.
決め手が見つからないという
状況かもしれません
話し合いをしましょう
Let us negotiate.
私は 塩屋虻コロニーの総司令官
野狐丸です
I am the supreme commander of
the Robber Fly colony, Yakomaru.
Shall we try to avoid more unnecessary bloodshed?
これ以上 無益な殺し合いは
やめにしませんか？
What a load of crap.
何をほざいてるんだ アイツは…
どうか私の声に答えてください
Please answer me.
人間とバケネズミは
Humans and queerats might be different races, but we are of similar intelligence.
種こそ違えど
知性を持った存在です
いかなる利害の相違が
あったとしても
Our interests may differ, but surely negotiations can overcome them.
全て話し合いによって
解決できるはずです
Engaging in dialogue would be the first step.
そのための第一歩としては
まず お互いに会話を…
答えてはいけません
Don’t answer him.
こちらの返事で
位置を確認するつもりです
They wish to use our voices to locate us.
覚 ごめんなさい
I’m sorry, Satoru.
私 バカだった
I was a fool.
覚も感染してしまうと
思ったから…
I was afraid you’d be infected too…
It’s okay. I understand.
いいって 分かってる
私 悪鬼と刺し違えるチャンスを
ドブに捨ててしまった
I ruined our chance to deal with the Fiend.
そのことを後悔しながら
死んでいくのね
I’m going to die regretting it.
我々の社会には
In our society, there is a saying that goes,
“complain to the grave worms
when you are lying next to them.”
｢繰り言は 墓穴に入ってから
ウジに聞かせろ｣という
ことわざがあります
皆さんは諦めが早すぎる
You are too fond of giving up.
我々の種族は 心臓が鼓動を止める
まさに その瞬間まで
Our kind seeks to find a way to turn
the tables until our dying moments.
逆転する方策を探し求めます
それが無駄な努力に
終わったところで
Though those efforts may be in vain, we lose nothing by trying.
失うものはありません
１つ聞いておきたいことがあるの
There’s something I’ve wanted to ask you.
何なりと
Go on.
昔 東京に来たのは何のためなの？
Why did you come to Tokyo all this time ago?
今さら
ごまかす必要もないでしょう
I suppose I can tell you now.
古代文明の遺物である
大量破壊兵器を入手するためです
We came to find weapons of mass destruction left behind by the ancient civilization.
人類にとって代わり
我々の覇権を打ち立てることも
With them we could have replaced humans as the dominant species on the planet.
不可能ではなくなります
I thought we were allies.
君たちとは良好な関係を
築いていたじゃないか
What are allies?
良好な関係とは何でしょう？
我々は人類に対し 忠誠を誓い
役務を提供することで
We swore loyalty to mankind and served you.
ようやく生存を許される立場です
That was the only way to ensure our survival.
But we had no way of telling when
the winds of fortune would change.
しかし それも いつ風向きが
変わるか分かりません
不可解な理由で
コロニーが抹殺されるのも
A number of colonies have been
wiped out for entirely obscure reasons.
珍しくはありません
人類を滅ぼす気だったの？
You wanted to destroy mankind?
勝つ見込みがあれば
そうしたかもしれません
We might have tried if there was a reasonable hope of success.
しかし ここでは
何も発見できませんでした
But we could not find anything here.
我々は いたずらに
人類を敵視しているわけでも
We were not trying to oppose mankind out of mere whim,
nor were we driven by a lust for conquest.
征服欲に とりつかれている
わけでもないのです
願いは
コロニーの存続と繁栄なのです
All we wished for was the survival and prosperity of our colony.
面白い
Interesting.
Kiroumaru may be the key to resolving this situation.
奇狼丸だよ
切り札になるかもしれない
あれは悪鬼じゃない
そのことを考えれば…
That’s not a Fiend. And if that’s the case…
分かってるだろう 君に見せたはず
You understand, don’t you?
I showed myself to you, up on the surface.
地上で 僕の姿… どうなったか
What happened to it?
What’s wrong, Saki?
早季 どうしたんだ？
あのね…
I think—
来ます
He is coming.
悪鬼が
The Fiend is coming.
あと もう２ｍ～３ｍ…
He is two or three meters away.
通り過ぎました
He has passed by.
He must have joined Yakomaru and the others.
野狐丸たちと合流するんでしょう
どうなってるんだ
なんで見逃したんだろ？
What’s going on? Why didn’t he attack?
They might be afraid we might launch a suicide attack against Yakomaru.
我々が野狐丸側に向かって
特攻をかけるのを
恐れたのかもしれません
お二人のうち １人が生き残れば
If either of you survived long enough, you could kill them all.
やつらを皆殺しにできますから
しかし 合流によって
However, now that they have reunited, we can retreat that way.
我々には
退路ができたことになります
It might be an attempt to force our hand.
逃げろという誘いなのか
それとも…
わなでも逃げるべきだ
今を逃したらチャンスはない
We should escape even if it’s a trap.
There won’t be another chance.
Wait. That’s not a Fiend.
待って！ あれは悪鬼じゃない
早季
Saki?
We were so ignorant.
私たちの目は節穴だった
今まで絶好の機会は
何度も訪れていたのに
There were countless chances, yet we simply folded our arms let them all slip away.
ただ 手をこまねいて
見送ってきたんだわ
どういうことですか？
What do you mean?
We might still have a chance.
だけど まだチャンスは
あるかもしれない
It’s harder than ever, but…
さっきより難しくなったけど…
いや でも うまく逆手にとって…
Well… We can still turn it all around.
早季 頼むから
分かるように言ってくれ
Saki?
Please, try to make some sense.
あったの
We can do it.
倒せる方法が
We can defeat him.
Nani mo iranai
何もいらない
I need nothing else
Anata ga ireba ii
あなたがいればいい
When you are by my side
Sotto yokogao iki wo korosu
そっと横顔 息を殺す
I look at you in profile and hold my breath
Mabataki sureba kieteshimaisou de
まばたきすれば消えてしまいそうで
I'm afraid it might vanish like an illusion if I blink now
Mitsumesasete suki da yo
凝視めさせて好きだよ
Let me look at you, I love you
Ah kigi ga furue furidashita yuki
ああ 木々が震え 降り出した雪
The trees shake in the wind and snow gathers on the ground
Ashiato futatsu shiroku
足跡 ふたつ 白く
Two lines of white footprints show
Toki yo tsumore
時よ 積もれ
Snowflakes of time, gather
Kami ni mune ni futari dake no yume ni
髪に 胸に ふたりだけの夢に
In our hair, our hearts, our dream
Sakenai hana no
咲けない花の
This flower cannot bloom
Tane wa yuki ni dakare
種は雪に抱かれ
And the snow embraces its seeds
Yorisou no
寄り添うの
As they huddle together
Shizuka ni wasureraretai
静かに忘れられたい
Quietly they wish to be able to forget
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD